<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अधिमन्त्रम् on संस्कारे विश्वासटिप्पणयः</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अधिमन्त्रम् on संस्कारे विश्वासटिप्पणयः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/consciousness/</guid>
      <description>Intro Via MT:
I would say the mantra-s are conscious (rather than living) with shabda-tanu just as a living being is conscious with an ANava-tanu. The other sounds are conscious too just as a stone or dead wood is conscious but they are almost entirely of the guNa tamas.
However, a mantra like a living organism has the additional enrichment of sattva which impinges on that consciousness. That makes them different from just a random sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaning</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/meaning/</guid>
      <description>Intro  To understand what a mantra says and, to feel what the mantra feels: This is one good reason why learning Sanskrit, with its stresses (svara-s) is valuable. General background on multi-level ways to derive meaning out of texts in general is presented here.  Meaning denouncers  Some claim that it is not necessary to understand what the words in the mantra mean (to whatever extant the grammar would allow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>देवाः</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/deva-parichayaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/deva-parichayaH/</guid>
      <description>प्रवेशः  &amp;ldquo;The deva-s started unveiling themselves: the upward blaze of agni in the three stations, the power of vAyu, the all-encompassing indra, the natural conservations of mitra, the natural laws whose violations are punished by varuNa, the exhilaration of knowing the natural law in aryaman, the swift transmission of the maruts, the dissolution of natural bonds through their father, the archer rudra, the light of savitA, the warmth of puShA, distribution of energies through bhaga, the flow of time in viShNu, the Milky way and the earthly flows of sarasvatI, the chemistry of the ashvins, the clear reflection by bR^ihaspati, the revolutions and the cycles of the observable cosmos in soma and tvaShTa with the R^ibhus, the world axis and its precessions in Aja-ekapAd and ahir-budhnya, the origins in aditi and then the mysterious prajApati called ka, and national identity in the 3 goddess ilA, sarasvatI and bhAratI&amp;rdquo; MT तत्तद्देवपरिचयस् तत्तत्-पृष्ठे दृश्यताम्। यथा देवानाम् इन्द्रस्यात्र!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>पितरः</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/pitaraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/saMskAra/mantraH/meta/pitaraH/</guid>
      <description>परिचयः  Hearn - &amp;ldquo;Well, I think we Occidentals have yet to learn the worship of ancestors; and evolution is going to teach it to us. When we become conscious that we owe whatever is wise or good or strong or beautiful in each one of us, not to one particular inner individuality, but to the struggles and sufferings and experiences of the whole unknown chain of human lives behind us, reaching back into mystery unthinkable - the worship of ancestors seems an extremely righteous thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>